[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
DAVID MALAN: This is CS50's Introduction to Programming with Python.
David Malan：这是CS50的S介绍使用Python语言编程
My name is David Malan, and this week we focus on conditionals.
我的名字是大卫·马兰 本周我们关注的是条件句
Conditionals, or conditional statements, in Python and in other languages,
条件句 或条件语句 在Python和其他语言中
are this ability to ask questions and answer those questions, in order
问问题和回答问题的能力是按顺序的吗？
to decide do you want to execute this line of code?
来决定是否要执行此行代码？
Or this line of code?
还是这行代码？
Or this other line of code instead?
还是这一行代码呢？
They allow you to take the proverbial forks in the road,
他们允许你在路上走谚语中的分叉口
within your own code, logically.
在您自己的代码中 逻辑上
So how might we go about making some of these decisions?
那么 我们该如何着手做出其中一些决定呢？
Well, it turns out that Python comes with a lot of built-in syntax.
好的 事实证明 Python附带了很多内置语法
For instance, here are just some of the symbols
例如 这里只是其中的一些符号
you can use in Python to ask questions.
您可以在Python中使用来提出问题
Admittedly, mathematical questions, but we'll start there, if only
诚然 数学问题 但我们将从那里开始 如果
to keep the examples simple early on.
为了在早期保持示例的简单性
This first symbol, as you might know from math, represents greater than.
第一个符号 正如你可能从数学中知道的 代表大于
The second symbol might not look too familiar, because we usually write it
第二个符号可能看起来不太眼熟 因为我们通常写它
all as one thing on a piece of paper.
这一切都像一张纸上的一件事
But on a keyboard, if you want to say greater than or equal to,
但在键盘上 如果你想说大于或等于
you'd use this symbol instead.
你可以用这个符号来代替
This, of course, means less than.
当然 这意味着不到
This means less than or equal to.
这意味着小于或等于
And this one's a bit of a curiosity.
这是一件有点好奇的事
We've seen, in our look at functions and variables,
我们已经看到 在我们研究函数和变量时
how we were able to assign values to variables using a single equal sign.
我们是如何用一个等号给变量赋值的
But that equal sign didn't represent equality.
但这个等号并不代表平等
It represented assignment, from right to left.
它代表从右到左的任务
That's great, because it solved that problem.
这太好了 因为它解决了这个问题
But it left us in a bit of a bind, because how do we now
但它给我们留下了一点束缚 因为我们现在如何
compare two things, left and right?
比较两个东西 左边和右边？
Well, in Python, and in many languages, you actually use two equal sides.
在Python语言中 以及在许多语言中 您实际上使用了两个相等的边
So two equal signs represents equality, comparing the thing
因此 两个等号代表平等 比较事物
on the left and the right.
在左边和右边
One equal sign, as always, represents assignment,
一个等号 一如既往地代表赋值
copying the thing from the right to the left.
把东西从右边复制到左边
Lastly, this last symbol represents not equal to.
最后 最后一个符号表示不等于
So the exclamation point, or bang, followed by an equal sign,
所以感叹号 或bang 后面跟着一个等号
means not equal to some value next to it.
表示不等于它旁边的某个值
Well, to ask the questions using these symbols, or any others,
好的 用这些符号或其他任何符号来提问
we're going to need another keyword in Python.
我们将需要在Python中使用另一个关键字
And that keyword, quite simply, as in English, is if.
这个关键字很简单 就像在英语中一样 就是if
You can ask questions in Python code along the lines of,
您可以在Python代码中提出如下问题：
if the answer to this question is true, then go ahead
如果这个问题的答案是真的 那就说吧
and execute this code for me.
帮我执行这段代码
So let's go ahead and write some of these examples here.
所以让我们继续在这里写一些这样的例子
I'm going to go over to VS Code.
我将转到VS代码
And let's go ahead and create a program first,
让我们先来创建一个程序
called compare.py, the goal of which is simply
它的目标是简单地
to write code that compares values and makes decisions based on those values.
编写比较值并根据这些值做出决策的代码
Let's go ahead and type code of compare.py,
让我们继续输入comare.py代码
in order to create a brand new file called compare,
为了创建一个名为Compare的全新文件
in which we'll start to express some of this logic.
我们将开始表达其中的一些逻辑
Well, what do we want to compare?
那么 我们想要比较什么呢？
Suppose we want to compare, for the sake of discussion,
为了便于讨论 假设我们想要比较
just a couple of integers.
只有几个整数
But we'd like those integers to come from the user,
但我们希望这些整数来自用户
so that we can make decisions based on numbers
这样我们就可以根据数字做出决定
we don't know the values of in advance.
我们不知道预付款的价值
Well, let's go ahead and do this.
好吧 让我们继续做这件事
As we've done in the past, let's declare it a variable, like x.
正如我们在过去所做的那样 让我们将其声明为一个变量 如x
Let's assign it equal to the return value of the int function,
让我们将其赋值为int函数的返回值
and pass to the int function the return value of the input function,
并将输入函数的返回值传递给INT函数
asking the user a question like, what's x, question
问用户一个问题 比如 什么是x 问题
mark, as we've done in the past.
马克 就像我们过去做的那样
Let's do this one more time with y, asking the user for the value of y.
让我们对y再做一次 询问用户y的值
And, again, converting that, ultimately, to an int, as well.
再一次 最终将其转换为int
So with this amount of the story, we have two variables, x and y,
有了这个故事的数量 我们有两个变量 x和y
each of which has values.
其中每一个都有其价值
And ideally, we should be able to now compare these values.
理想情况下 我们现在应该能够比较这些值
So suppose I want to make a decision based on the values of these variables.
假设我想要根据这些变量的值做出决定
I'm going to use the keyword if.
我将使用关键字if
And I'm going to use some of those mathematical symbols
我将使用其中一些数学符号
to actually ask the question itself.
才能真正问出问题本身
So how about this, if x is less than y, then let's go ahead and just
这样如何 如果x小于y 那么让我们继续
print as much out.
打印出尽可能多的内容
Quote, unquote x is less than y.
引用 无引号的x小于y
So this isn't a very interesting program yet.
所以这还不是一个很有趣的项目
I'm literally just stating the obvious, based on the math.
从字面上讲 我只是在根据数学原理陈述显而易见的事情
But it's allowing me to now introduce some new syntax.
但它允许我现在引入一些新的语法
And exactly what is the syntax?
具体的语法是什么？
Well, it's this-- not just the keyword if, which
嗯 它是这样的--不仅仅是关键字if 哪
I've added here at the start of line four,
我已经在第四行的开头添加了
but then I asked my question here, x less than y.
然后我在这里问了我的问题 x小于y
x is one variable on the left, y is one variable on the right.
X是左边的一个变量 y是右边的一个变量
And, of course, the less than sign is expressing the mathematical question
当然 小于号表示数学问题
I have.
我有过
What I've highlighted here is technically
我在这里强调的是从技术上讲
called a Boolean expression.
称为布尔表达式
A Boolean expression, named after a mathematician named Bool,
一个布尔表达式 以数学家布尔来命名
is simply a question that has a yes or no answer, or technically,
仅仅是一个有是或否答案的问题 或者从技术上讲
a true or false answer.
正确或错误的答案
And that's nice because if there's only two possible answers,
这很好 因为如果只有两个可能的答案
it's very easy for me, and in turn the computer, to make a decision--
对我和电脑来说 做决定非常容易--
do this, or don't do this thing.
做这件事 否则别做这件事
Now notice, if you come from other languages,
现在注意 如果你来自其他语言
you might notice that I have not typed any parentheses.
您可能注意到 我没有键入任何括号
They are not, in fact, necessary, at least in this case, in Python,
事实上 它们不是必需的 至少在这种情况下 在Python中是不必要的
but I have typed a colon at the end of the line.
但我在行尾打了一个冒号
And even more importantly, at the next line
更重要的是 在下一行
I have begun my line with some indentation,
我的生产线一开始就有一些缩进
hitting the space bar four times, or just hitting Tab once,
按空格键四次 或者只按一次Tab键
which will automatically be converted to the same.
它将自动转换为相同的
That indentation is what tells Python that line five should only
这种缩进告诉Python 第五行应该只
be executed if the answer to line four's question is, in fact, true.
如果第四行问题的答案事实上是真的 则执行
So if x is less than y, that phrase will be printed thereafter.
因此 如果x小于y 则该短语将在之后打印
Well, let's add a few more lines of code.
那么 让我们再添加几行代码
How about another question?
再问一个问题怎么样？
If x is greater than y, then let's go ahead and print that.
如果x大于y 那么我们继续打印它
x is greater than y.
X大于y
And let's do one final question, if x equals y, then-- wait a minute.
让我们做最后一个问题 如果x等于y 那么--等一下
What have I done wrong here?
我在这里做错了什么？
A good eye here.
这里有一只好眼睛
I don't want to assign y to x.
我不想把y赋给x
If x equals equals y is how I express equality, let's go ahead
如果x等于y是我表达平等的方式 那么让我们继续
and print out x is equal to y.
打印输出x等于y
So I now have three conditions, if you will,
所以我现在有三个条件 如果你愿意的话
one question asking x less than y, one asking x greater than y,
一个问题问x小于y 另一个问题问x大于y
one asking x equals equals y.
一次求x等于y
Let's run the code.
让我们运行代码
Well, down here in my terminal window I'm
嗯 在我的终端窗口里 我
going to run Python of compare.py and hit Enter.
运行Compare.py的Python并按Enter键
What's x?
X是什么？
Let's go with one.
那我们就选一个吧
What's y?
你是什么？
Let's go with two.
我们选两个吧
This should, of course, execute that first line of code
当然 这应该执行第一行代码
and tell me, indeed, that x is less than y.
告诉我 实际上 x小于y
Exactly as I would expect there.
正如我在那里所期望的那样
Well, what just happened, though, in code?
好吧 刚才发生了什么 不过 用代码？
Well, let's take a look, perhaps, at this same code visually,
好吧 让我们来看看 也许 从视觉上看同样的代码
particularly if you're a more visual learner, this, I dare say,
尤其是如果你是一个更直观的学习者 我敢说
is what just happened.
就是刚刚发生的事情
So what we're looking at here is a flow chart.
所以我们现在看到的是一个流程图
It's a diagram of this program's logic.
这是这个程序的逻辑示意图
And more technically, it shows the program's control flow.
从技术上讲 它显示了程序的控制流
That is, the ability of you, in code, to control
也就是说 您在代码中控制
the flow of a program, generally from top to bottom.
程序的流动 通常是从上到下
In fact, let me go ahead and zoom in on the top of this flow chart.
事实上 让我继续放大这个流程图的顶部
And you'll see an oval at the very top that says, quite literally, start.
你会在最上面看到一个椭圆形 字面上写着 开始
That is, irrespective of what shape or layout
也就是说 无论是什么形状或布局
the diagram is, where your own thinking and logic
这张图是 你自己的思维和逻辑
should start when trying to wrap your mind around this program.
当你试图将你的注意力集中在这个程序上时 应该开始
Notice that there's an arrow from start to this diamond shape.
请注意 从Start到这个钻石形状有一个箭头
And inside of that diamond is a question, a Boolean expression,
在那个钻石的内部是一个问题 一个布尔表达式
x less than y.
X小于y
And this shape just means, based on the answer to that question,
这个形状意味着 根据这个问题的答案
go left or go right.
往左走还是往右走
Specifically, go left if the answer is true,
具体来说 如果答案是真的 就向左转
or go right if the answer is false.
或者 如果答案为假 则选择正确的答案
Well, the inputs I typed were one and two, respectively, for x and y.
我输入的是1和2 分别代表x和y
So, of course, one is less than two.
当然 一比二小
So that's why my program printed out, quote unquote, x is less than y.
这就是为什么我的程序会打印出来 引用引号 x小于y
But recall the code.
但记住密码
The code then proceeded to ask two more questions.
代码接着又问了两个问题
Is x greater than y?
x大于y？
Is x equal equal to y?
x等于y吗？
Well, the flow chart depicts those questions, too.
流程图也描述了这些问题
Notice that no matter whether the question
请注意 无论问题是否
had an answer of true or false, the arrows both converge back down
当我得到一个正确或错误的答案时 两个箭头都会聚下来
to this second diamond shape here.
到第二个菱形
And that second diamond shape asks the second question, x greater than y.
第二个菱形问第二个问题 x大于y
That, too, has a true or false answer.
这也有一个正确或错误的答案
So we go one way or the other.
所以我们只能选择一条路
But if x is one and y is two, then no, the answer is false.
但如果x是1 y是2 那么答案是否定的
One is not greater than y.
1不大于y
So logically, in the flow chart, you follow the false arrow this time.
所以从逻辑上讲 在流程图中 这次你沿着错误的箭头走
And notice, along that false arrow you don't print anything this time.
注意 沿着那个假箭头 这次您没有打印任何内容
That's why we only saw one printout on the screen.
所以我们在屏幕上只看到一个人
Now, there was still a third question.
现在 还有第三个问题
And this flow chart captures that, as well.
这个流程图也体现了这一点
The third diamond asks x equals equals y.
第三个菱形问x等于y
Now that, too, has a false answer in this case, because one, of course,
在这个例子中 也有一个错误的答案 因为 当然
does not equal equal y.
不等于y
And so we again follow the third false branch here.
因此 我们再次遵循第三个错误分支
And that leads us, of course, to stop.
这导致我们 当然 停下来
And stop just indicates that's it for the program.
停止只是表示程序到此为止
So I think that's correct.
所以我认为这是正确的
And that particular flow chart does happen
这个流程图确实
to represent the actual code that I wrote.
来表示我写的代码
So it's correct.
所以是正确的
It does what it's supposed to do.
它做了它应该做的
It answered the question correctly by printing on the screen x less than y.
它通过在屏幕上打印x小于y正确地回答了这个问题
But what is, perhaps, poorly designed about it?
但是 也许是什么设计不好呢？
Let's make this first distinction.
让我们做第一个区分
It's not enough, necessarily, for the code
但这并不足以
that you write to be correct and do what you intend.
你写的是正确的 做你想做的
Longer term, especially as our programs get longer and more sophisticated,
从长远来看 特别是随着我们的项目变得越来越长 越来越复杂
more complicated, we're going to want them to be well-designed, too.
更复杂 我们也希望它们设计得很好
Thoughts on in what way this program is arguably not well designed,
关于这个项目在哪些方面设计得不好的想法
even though it's correct?
即使它是正确的
Let's see here.
我看看
Khalid, if I'm saying that right, your thoughts?
卡里德 如果我说的没错 你的想法是什么？
KHALID: Too many ifs, I think, is getting repetitive.
哈立德：太多的如果 我认为 变得重复
We can make our code more concise, maybe.
也许我们可以让代码更简洁
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, it seems a little repetitive.
大卫·马兰：是的 这似乎有点重复
I'm asking if this, if this, if this.
我是问如果这个 如果这个 如果这个
And yet, logically, I should know the answer to some of those later questions
然而 从逻辑上讲 我应该知道后面那些问题的答案
once I figure one out.
一旦我想出一个
And, in short, if you look at this diagram here,
简而言之 如果你看这张图
notice that no matter whether I go left or I go right,
请注意 无论我是向左还是向右
I'm always asking three questions.
我总是问三个问题
No matter what, all of those arrows lead to the first, the second,
不管怎样 所有的箭头都指向第一个 第二个
and the third diamond.
第三颗钻石
So I'm asking three questions, no matter whether any of those answers
所以我要问三个问题 不管这些答案中的任何一个
are true or false.
是真是假
Well how might I go about improving this?
我该如何改进呢？
Well, let me propose that we introduce another keyword
好吧 让我提议我们引入另一个关键词
to our Python vocabulary, namely elif.
我们的Python词汇表 即elif
And this, too, is kind of a succinct one.
这也是一个简洁的例子
It's a conjunction of else if, in English,
在英语中 它是else if的连词
which allows us to ask a question that takes into account whether or not
这让我们可以提出一个问题
a previous question had a true or false answer.
前一个问题有一个正确或错误的答案
Well, what do I mean by that?
我这么说是什么意思
Well, let me go back to my code here.
好吧 让我回到我的代码
And let me propose that we now improve upon this, here,
让我提议我们现在改进这个 在这里
by asking ourselves, ultimately, how can we ask fewer questions?
通过问我们自己 最终 我们怎么能少问些问题？
And let me go ahead here and propose that
让我在这里提出
instead of asking if, if, if, let's make these conditions potentially mutually
而不是问如果 让我们使这些条件潜在地相互
exclusive.
独家新闻
That is to say, don't keep answering questions once we get back
也就是说 回去以后不要再回答问题了
a true answer.
一个真实的答案
So I'm going to change my code up here as follows.
所以我将修改代码如下
Instead of asking if, if, if, I'm going to say, if x less than y, elif x
而不是问如果 我会说 如果x小于y
greater than y, elif x equals equals y.
大于y 如果x等于y
So I'm going to implicitly, just like an English,
所以我要含蓄地 就像英国人一样
take into account that I'm only going to keep asking myself these questions
考虑到我只会不断地问自己这些问题
if I haven't yet gotten a true response.
如果我还没有得到一个真实的回应
Think about the logic here, the English.
想想这里的逻辑 英国人
If x is less than y, on line four, print out x is less than y.
如果x小于y 则在第四行 打印输出x小于y
Well, if that's the case, you're done, logically.
好吧 如果是这样的话 从逻辑上讲 你就完了
Because if the English is saying if x less than y, else if x greater than y,
因为如果英国人说如果x小于y 否则如果x大于y
those are going to be mutually exclusive if the answer to the first question
如果第一个问题的答案是相互排斥的
is true.
是真的
You don't have to keep asking questions to which you already logically know
你不必一直问你在逻辑上已经知道的问题
the answer.
答案就是
So let me go ahead now and run this program.
现在让我继续运行这个程序
And I think the behavior is going to be the same.
我认为他们的行为会是一样的
Python of compare.py, what's x?
Py的蟒蛇 x是什么？
Let's do one.
让我们来做一个吧
What's y?
你是什么？
Let's do two.
让我们来做两个
x is less than y.
X小于y
Now, honestly, I didn't really notice a difference when I ran the program.
现在 老实说 当我运行这个程序时 我并没有真正注意到什么不同
And honestly, my Mac, my PC, my phone nowadays,
老实说 我的Mac 我的PC 我的手机
are so darn fast that these kinds of improvements
是如此之快 以至于这些改进
aren't going to necessarily feel any faster until we're
不一定会感觉更快 直到我们
writing bigger, faster programs.
编写更大、更快的程序
But it's laying the foundation for writing better code longer term.
但从长远来看 它正在为编写更好的代码奠定基础
Now what is the improvement I've just made?
现在 我刚刚取得的进步是什么？
Well, if previously my diagram looked like this,
嗯 如果之前我的图表是这样的
which was problematic insofar as I was asking three questions no matter
这是有问题的 因为我问了三个问题
what, even if I already figured out what I want to print on the screen.
什么 即使我已经想好了要在屏幕上打印什么
This new version of the program that says if, elif, elif, might look
这个新版本的程序说 如果 埃利夫 埃利夫 可能看起来
a little something like this instead.
而是像这样的小东西
Now it got a little wider.
现在 它变得更宽了一点
That's just because we drew the arrows to be a bit wider here.
这只是因为我们把这里的箭头画得更宽了一点
But let's focus on just how many questions are getting asked.
但让我们关注一下有多少问题被问到了
Let me zoom in at the top, as before.
像以前一样 让我放大顶部
And let me propose that we note that the start oval is at the very top,
让我提议 我们注意到 开始椭圆形在最上面
and it's asking us to ask one question first.
它要求我们先问一个问题
x less than y, is one less than two?
X比y小 一比二小吗？
But notice here, let me zoom out, if one is, indeed, less
但请注意 让我放大 如果确实是这样的话
than two, we follow this longer arrow down, marked true.
超过两个 我们沿着这个更长的箭头向下 标记为真
We print out quote, unquote x is less than y.
我们打印出报价 不引用的x小于y
But then we immediately follow this next arrow down to the icon that says stop.
然后 我们立即沿着下一个箭头向下 找到一个图标 上面写着停止
So that's what's implied by doing if, elif, elif.
所以这就是做If Elif Elif所暗示的
If we get back a true answer right away to that first if,
如果我们马上得到第一个假设的真实答案
we're going to print out x is less than y and then stop.
我们要打印出x小于y 然后停止
We're logically at the end of the program.
从逻辑上讲 我们已经到了节目的末尾
So this picture is just representing, graphically,
因此 这张图片只是以图形的形式呈现
what the code is actually doing.
代码实际在做什么
But suppose I typed in something else.
但假设我输入了其他内容
Suppose that my code actually ran, and I typed in two for x and one for y.
假设我的代码真的运行了 我为x输入了两个 为y输入了一个
That is to say, the answer to the first question is now false.
也就是说 第一个问题的答案现在是假的
But the answer to the second question is now true.
但第二个问题的答案现在是正确的
Because, of course, two is greater than one.
因为 当然 二比一大
Well, let's go back to the diagram.
好了 让我们回到图表上
Same as before, we start at the very top where it says start.
和以前一样 我们从最上面写着开始的地方开始
The very first question up here, now, x less than y, is an answer of false,
这里的第一个问题 现在 x小于y 是一个假的答案
because no, two is not less than one.
因为不 两个不少于一个
So we follow this arrow to the next question, this diamond.
所以我们顺着这个箭头到下一个问题 这颗钻石
Is x greater than y?
X比y大吗？
Well, yes, two is greater than one.
是的 两个人总比一个人强
So now we follow this left arrow, which is true.
现在我们沿着这个向左的箭头走 这是真的
We print out quote, unquote x is greater than y, and then stop.
我们打印出引号 不引号x大于y 然后停止
So what's the improvement?
那么 有什么改进呢？
Well, in the first case, we got lucky and we only
在第一个案例中 我们很幸运 我们只
had to ask one question and boom, we're done.
只要问一个问题 砰 我们就完了
This time, we had to ask two questions, but then boom, we're done.
这一次 我们不得不问两个问题 但然后砰的一声 我们就完了
Only if x happens to equal y do we actually find ourselves, logically,
只有当x恰好等于y时 我们才能真正发现自己 在逻辑上
getting all the way down to this final elif in my code.
在我的代码中一直到最后的elif
And pictorially, only if x is equal to y do
在图画上 只有当x等于y时才会这样做
we find ourselves going all the way down to the third diamond,
我们发现我们一直走到了第三个钻石
the third question, asking is it equal to y or not?
第三个问题 问它是否等于y？
Now, hopefully, the answer at that point is not false.
现在 希望在这一点上 答案不是错误的
We've included a false arrow just so that the program itself
我们包含了一个错误的箭头 这样程序本身
is well-defined.
是定义明确的
But, logically, we shouldn't actually be getting there anyway,
但是 从逻辑上讲 我们无论如何都不应该真正做到这一点
because it's got to be less than, or greater than, or equal to in this case.
因为在这种情况下 它必须小于、大于或等于
Well, let me pause here to see if there's
好吧 让我在这里停一下 看看有没有
any questions, now, either on the code version thereof here,
任何问题 现在 无论是关于这里的代码版本
or on this diagramming of that very same logic.
或者在这个同样的逻辑的图表上
Questions here, on this control flow?
关于这个控制流有什么问题吗？
SPEAKER 1: Aren't we supposed to put an else at the end?
演讲者1：我们不是应该在末尾再加一个吗？
DAVID MALAN: A good question.
大卫·马兰：问得好
And yes-- so that's going to be my third and final approach.
是的 这将是我的第三个也是最后一个方法
And if you don't mind, let's pivot there right away.
如果你不介意的话 我们现在就转到那里去
Identifying a third keyword, that indeed exists
确定第三个确实存在的关键字
in Python, that allows us to be even better at expressing this logic
在Python中 这使我们能够更好地表达这一逻辑
to design this program even better.
把这个程序设计得更好
And that's going to solve a particular problem.
这将解决一个特殊的问题
So if I take us back to our code here, notice
所以如果我把我们带回这里的代码 请注意
that what I've highlighted earlier, elif x equals equals y.
这就是我前面强调的 elif x等于y
It's not wrong to ask that question.
问那个问题并没有错
In fact, if you're trying to be especially thorough,
事实上 如果你想要特别彻底
it makes perfect sense to check if x is less than y, greater than y,
检查x是否小于y 是否大于y是非常有意义的
or equal to y.
或等于y
But why don't I need to ask this third and final question?
但为什么我不需要问第三个也是最后一个问题呢？
SPEAKER 2: We don't need to ask if x is equal to y any more because, logically,
演讲者2：我们不需要再问x是否等于y了 因为从逻辑上讲
if the two conditionals evaluate to false,
如果这两个条件语句的计算结果为假
there is only one conditional that will evaluate to true.
只有一个条件的计算结果为真
And that is x is equal to y.
也就是说 x等于y
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
大卫·马兰：没错
If we're all pretty comfortable with math, and comparisons
如果我们都对数学和比较很满意
here, of course x is either going to be less than y, greater than y,
这里 当然 x要么小于y 要么大于y
or equal to y.
或等于y
But once you rule out the first two scenarios,
但一旦你排除了前两种情况
logically, it's got to be the case that x must equal y.
从逻辑上讲 它必须是x等于y的情况
If it wasn't the case, then it's less than or greater than.
如果不是这样 那么它就是小于或大于
So Hope proposed that we use this other keyword, else.
所以霍普建议我们使用另一个关键字 Else
And how do we use this?
我们如何利用这一点呢？
Well, exactly as we might in English.
嗯 跟我们用英语说的一模一样
Let me go back to my code here.
让我在这里回到我的代码
And instead of bothering to ask the third and final question,
而不是费心去问第三个也是最后一个问题
let's not ask a question at all.
我们什么都别问了
Let's just have this catch-all. so to speak, a final line of code that says,
就让我们来个包罗万象的吧 可以这么说 最后一行代码说
else just assume that x is equal to y.
否则就假设x等于y
Therefore, printing it as well.
因此 也要把它打印出来
So what's the upside of that?
那么 这有什么好处呢？
My code is still going to work exactly the same.
我的代码仍将以完全相同的方式工作
And again, my computer is so darn fast, I
再说一次 我的电脑太快了 我
don't even notice that it's working even faster than it was before.
甚至没有注意到它的工作速度比以前更快
But we would notice these kinds of things
但我们会注意到这类事情
if we were doing a lot more work, a lot bigger programs here.
如果我们在这里做更多的工作 更大的项目
But let me run Python of compare.py.
但让我运行Compare.py的Python
Let's do, for instance, one and two.
让我们来做 例如 一和二
Still works for that.
对这一点仍然有效
Let's do two and one.
让我们做二和一
Let's do one and one.
让我们做一次和一次
And it, indeed, now works for that.
事实上 它现在对此起到了作用
But in these cases now, let's consider the path we just went down.
但在这些情况下 让我们考虑一下我们刚刚走过的道路
Previously, our diagram, when we had if, elif, elif in place,
之前 我们的图表 当我们有If Elif Elif到位时
looked a little something like this.
看起来有点像这样
And notice, they began, we might have asked one question, or two,
注意 他们开始说 我们可能问了一两个问题
or worst case, three whole questions.
或者最坏的情况 三个完整的问题
But we can do better than that, using else, as Hope proposed,
但我们可以做得更好 就像霍普建议的那样 使用其他方法
we can whittle this diagram, now, down to this.
现在 我们可以把这张图削成这样
And even though it looks like the diagram's getting bigger,
尽管这张图看起来越来越大
notice that it's having fewer building blocks inside of it.
请注意 它内部的构建块更少了
There's fewer arrows and there's fewer nodes in this picture.
这张图中的箭头和节点都比较少
Let's start at the top now.
现在让我们从顶层开始
Start leads us to the first question, still. x less than y?
尽管如此 START仍然将我们引向第一个问题 X比Y小？
If the answer is true, great.
如果答案是真的 那就太好了
We can say as much, x is less than y, and we can stop.
我们可以说 x小于y 我们可以停止
If it's not true, if it's false, we can ask the next question.
如果不是真的 如果是假的 我们可以问下一个问题
x is greater than y, true or false?
X大于y 对还是错？
If it is, great.
如果是的话 那就太好了
We can print x is greater than y, and stop.
我们可以打印x大于y 然后停止
Else, if it's not the case that x is greater than y, the answer is false.
否则 如果不是x大于y的情况 答案是假的
We can just immediately, logically, say x is equal to y.
我们可以立即 从逻辑上说 x等于y
We don't have to add the third question at all.
我们根本不需要添加第三个问题
We can just immediately conclude there.
我们可以立即在那里得出结论
So what's the implication here?
那么 这意味着什么呢？
You can see, with these pictures, a relative decrease
从这些图片中你可以看到
in the complexity of a program.
一个程序的复杂性
The first one was very long and stringy, with lots and lots of questions,
第一个很长很长 有很多很多问题
unnecessarily, ultimately.
不必要的 最终
The next one got a little shorter.
下一个更短了
And this one's even shorter still.
这个更短
And again, the fewer lines of code you have, the less likely
同样 代码行越少
you are, arguably, to make any mistakes.
你可以说会犯任何错误
The easier it is for other people to read.
别人就越容易读懂
And so, generally, this readability, this simplification,
所以 一般来说 这种可读性 这种简化
is, indeed, a good thing.
的确是件好事
Well, let's go ahead and add another piece of capability to Python,
好吧 让我们继续为Python添加另一项功能
and that's this one here.
就是这个
Just like in English, where you can ask this question or this other question,
就像在英语中 你可以问这个或那个问题
you can say the same thing in Python using literally this word or.
你可以在Python中用这个词或来表达同样的意思
So let me go back to my Python code here.
让我们回到我的Python代码
And let's propose how we might ask a couple of questions
让我们提出几个问题
at once this time, perhaps this time considering how we might ask not
这一次 也许这一次考虑如何我们可能会问不
whether or not it's greater than or equal to,
无论它是否大于或等于
and caring about the precise answer.
关心准确的答案
Let's take a coarser approach here.
让我们在这里采取一个粗略的方法
And let's just try to determine is x equal to y or not?
让我们来确定x是否等于y？
Well, let me go ahead and delete some of this code
好吧 让我删除一些代码
and change the question we're asking.
改变我们的问题
Let me do this-- well, if I care about whether it's equal or not,
让我这么做吧 如果我关心它是否相等
let's check the possible scenarios.
让我们看看可能的情况
If x is less than y or x is greater than y, let's go ahead
如果x小于y或者x大于y 我们继续
and print out x is not equal to y.
打印出来的x不等于y
Now why is that, no pun intended?
为什么 不是双关语？
If x is less than y, well, it's obviously not equal.
如果x小于y 那么 它显然不相等
If x is greater than y,
如果x大于y 显然不相等
So we can conclude x is not equal to y.
所以我们可以得出结论x不等于y
So if we, instead, want to make sure that it is equal to,
所以如果我们想确保它等于
we can just use Hope's else, using print quote, unquote x is equal to y.
我们可以用霍普的else 用引号 x等于y
And again, why is this?
这是为什么呢？
Well, if x is less than y, or x is greater than y,
如果x小于y 或者x大于y
they're obviously not equal.
它们显然是不相等的
Otherwise, logically, they must be equal, in fact.
否则 从逻辑上讲 它们实际上必须相等
So let's run this.
我们来运行这个
Let's go ahead and run Python of compare.py.
让我们继续运行Compare.py的Python
What's x?
X是什么？
One.
一
What's y?
你是什么？
Two.
二
OK, x is not equal to y.
好的 x不等于y
Let's do it again, put two for x, one for y. x is not equal to y.
让我们再来一次 x等于x y等于y x不等于y
And one third time, how about x is one and y is one.
第三次 x是一 y是一
x is now equal to y.
X现在等于y
Now if we want to compare that visually, too,
现在 如果我们也想进行视觉上的比较
let me propose that the picture looks a little something like this.
让我建议这张图片看起来有点像这样
And again, this is the exact same thing logically,
再一次 这在逻辑上是完全相同的
but it's a pictorial representation thereof.
但这只是它的图画表现
What's the first question?
第一个问题是什么？
Well, if x is less than y, well, then we follow the true arrow.
好的 如果x小于y 那么我们就沿着真箭头走
And we say quote, unquote x is not equal to y.
我们说引用 不引用的x不等于y
And then we stop.
然后我们停下来
But what if x is not less than y?
但如果x不小于y呢？
What if it's greater than y?
如果它大于y呢？
What if it's two and one, respectively?
如果分别是二和一呢？
Then the answer to x less than y, first question, is false.
那么 第一个问题 x小于y的答案是假的
So we go here.
所以我们就来这里
We ask the second question, because of the or,
我们问第二个问题 因为OR
and that asks is x greater than y?
那就是问x是不是大于y？
If so, notice this, we can kind of reuse some of the same parts of this picture,
如果是这样的话 注意这一点 我们可以重复使用这张图片的一些相同部分
and just say x is not equal to y.
就说x不等于y
We don't need to add arrows and ad boxes unnecessarily.
我们不需要不必要地增加箭头和广告框
We can reuse lines of code, parts of the picture, just as we have lines of code.
我们可以重复使用代码行 图片的一部分 就像我们拥有代码行一样
And then we stop.
然后我们停下来
Lastly, we have the following.
最后 我们有以下几点
If we know that x is not less than y, we know
如果我们知道x不小于y 我们就知道
that x is not greater than y, it must be the case that x equals y.
即x不大于y 则一定是x等于y的情况
We don't need to ask a third question, another diamond.
我们不需要问第三个问题 另一个钻石
We can just immediately print as much, and then say stop, as well.
我们可以立即打印同样多的内容 然后也可以说停止
Well, what could I do here?
那么 我在这里能做什么呢？
I bet I could improve this code slightly.
我打赌我可以稍微改进一下这段代码
And if we really want to be nitpicky, I would
如果我们真的想挑剔 我会
argue that this is now really just a minor refinement,
辩称这现在真的只是一个微小的改进
but it's a good habit to get into thinking about.
但这是一个值得深思的好习惯
Could my code be better?
我的代码还能更好吗？
Could my code be simpler?
我的代码可以更简单吗？
Could I improve this code further?
我可以进一步改进这个代码吗？
It's subtle, but could I improve the design?
这很微妙 但我能改进一下设计吗？
Could I ask fewer questions?
我能少问几个问题吗？
Could I tighten it up, so to speak?
可以这么说 我可以把它拧紧吗？
What do folks think?
人们是怎么想的？
SPEAKER 3: You can ask is x is just equal to y.
演讲者3：你可以问x等于y吗？
Then if you print x is equal to y, else x is not equal to y.
如果你打印的x等于y 否则x不等于y
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
大卫·马兰：太好了
Recall one of the other symbols we saw on the available list earlier.
回想一下我们之前在可用列表中看到的另一个符号
We can check not just less than, or greater than, or equal to.
我们不仅可以检查小于、大于或等于
We can literally ask the question is it not equal to?
我们可以从字面上问这个问题 它不等于吗？
Why are we wasting time asking if it's less than or if it's greater than?
为什么我们要浪费时间去问它是小于还是大于？
Well, if all you care about is is it not equal, I think we can do exactly that.
嗯 如果你关心的是它是不是不平等 我认为我们可以做到这一点
Let's just ask the one simple question we do care about.
让我们只问一个我们真正关心的简单问题
And so let me go back up here.
所以让我回到这里
And let me just say not both of these questions, let's get rid of the or.
我只想说 不是这两个问题 让我们把OR去掉
Let's just say if x is not equal to y, then go
这么说吧 如果x不等于y 那么
ahead and print x is not equal to y.
并且打印x不等于y
And that, too, I think is going to work exactly the same.
而且 我认为这也会起到完全相同的作用
But the picture now looks a little bit different.
但现在的情况看起来有点不同
Notice that this was our flow chart earlier,
请注意 这是我们之前的流程图
that represented that same logic.
这代表了同样的逻辑
And there's a bit of complexity.
这其中有一点复杂
You've got to go left, you've got to go right,
你必须左转 你必须右转
based on the answer to these couple of questions.
基于对这两个问题的回答
If we now take into account what this version of the program looks like,
如果我们现在考虑到这个版本的程序是什么样子的
it's even simpler, perhaps the simplest one we've seen yet.
它甚至更简单 也许是我们见过的最简单的一个
When we start off the program, we ask just one, and only one, question,
当我们开始节目时 我们只问一个 而且只有一个问题
is x not equal to y?
X不等于y吗？
And if so, true, we go ahead and print out x not equal to y.
如果是这样的话 我们继续打印x不等于y
If the answer is false, then, of course, it must be equal to y,
如果答案为假 那么 当然 它必须等于y
so we say that instead.
因此 我们转而这么说
And if we really want, we could invert this.
如果我们真的想要的话 我们可以把它颠倒过来
If I go back here to my code, and if, for whatever reason,
如果我回到我的代码 如果 无论出于什么原因
you just prefer to think in terms of equal or not equal,
你只是更喜欢从平等或不平等的角度来思考
as opposed to not equal or equal, it's really up to you.
与不平等或不平等相反 这真的取决于你
We could change this to be equals equals.
我们可以把它改成相等
But I'm going to have to change my print statements to be in the opposite order.
但我将不得不将我的打印语句更改为相反的顺序
So let me go ahead, now, and reverse these two here,
所以现在让我继续 把这两个颠倒过来
and move the second one first and the first one second.
先移动第二个 然后再移动第一个
So now, when I execute this code, I'm asking still just one question.
所以现在 当我执行这段代码时 我仍然只问了一个问题
So it's still just as good, just as succinct.
所以它仍然一样好 一样简洁
But now the diagram, instead of looking like this,
但现在这张图不是这样的
is going to change the not equal to equal equal.
会把不等变成相等
And we just need to make sure that we print out the right thing, accordingly.
我们只需要确保相应地打印出正确的内容
And again, here too, just as the code is getting a little more compact, a little
在这里也是如此 就像代码变得更紧凑一样
more compact, with fewer and fewer characters,
更紧凑 字符越来越少
so are these diagrams, these flow charts capturing the relative simplification
这些图表也是如此 这些流程图捕捉到了相对简化的
of each of those programs, too.
这些节目中的每一个也是如此
Let me go ahead and pause here to see if there's any questions, now, on any
让我继续下去 在这里停下来看看是否有任何问题 现在 关于
of these versions of code.
这些版本的代码
SPEAKER 4: Yeah, I have a couple of questions.
演讲者4：是的 我有几个问题
What if indentation is not used?
如果不使用缩进怎么办？
DAVID MALAN: If indentation is not used, your program will not work.
David Malan：如果不使用缩进 您的程序将无法运行
So Python is a little different from a lot
所以 与很多不同的是
of languages in that it enforces the indentation requirement.
语言的一部分 因为它强制缩进要求
Some of you who have been programming for years
你们中一些已经编程多年的人
might not necessarily be in the best habit of indenting your code properly.
可能不一定是正确缩进代码的最佳习惯
And one of the features, arguably, of Python
可以说 Python的一个特性是
is that it makes you indent your code, or it will not just work.
它会让你缩进你的代码 否则它就不会正常工作
And I think, did you have one other question?
我想 你还有其他问题吗？
SPEAKER 4: Yeah, is the colon necessary?
演讲者4：是的 有必要做结肠吗？
DAVID MALAN: Is the colon necessary?
大卫·马兰：结肠是必要的吗？
Yes, the colon, too, is necessary.
是的 冒号也是必要的
So with Python, what you see is what you get here.
因此 使用Python时 您所看到的就是您在这里获得的内容
And, indeed, it needs to be indented and the colon is necessary.
事实上 它需要缩进 冒号是必要的
Python does not use, in the same way by convention as C, and C++, and Java,
按照约定 Python不像C、C++和Java那样使用
curly braces to connote blocks.
花括号表示块的含义
Instead, it relies, indeed, on this indentation.
相反 它确实依赖于这种缩进
Well, let me propose that we introduce one other keyword here in Python,
好吧 让我建议我们在这里引入另一个关键字
to see exactly how we might combine additional thoughts.
看看我们如何结合更多的想法
And that's going to be literally the word and, a conjunction of one,
这将是字面上的单词 和 一个连词
or two, or more questions that we might want to ask at once.
或者两个 或者更多的问题
And let me propose, here, that we explore this kind of logic
让我在这里提议 我们来探索这种逻辑
by way of another program altogether, in VS Code, whereby I'll go ahead now
通过另一个程序 在VS代码中 我现在将继续
and create a new program, say, called grade.py.
创建一个新的程序 比如说 叫grade.py
Let's consider exactly what grade a student should get,
让我们考虑一下学生应该得到什么分数
based on their score on an exam, or a test, or a quiz,
根据他们在考试中的分数 或者测试 或者测验
or some other assignment like that.
或者其他类似的任务
I'm going to go ahead and run code of grade.py, to give myself a new file.
我将继续运行grade.py的代码 给自己一个新文件
And I'm going to go ahead and start by just getting the user's score, again,
我将继续 从用户的分数开始
on some assignment, or test, or the like.
做作业或考试之类的
And I'm going to store it in a variable called score, equal the return
我会把它存储在一个变量score中 等于收益
value of the int function, which is going to convert whatever the user's
int函数的值 该函数将转换用户的
input is when prompted for this score.
输入是在提示输入该分数时
So again, the user should just oblige by giving me a number like zero, or one,
所以 用户应该给我一个数字 比如0 或者1
or two, or hopefully much higher than that, like 97, 98, 99, 100,
或者两个 或者更高 比如97 98 99 100
assuming the test or assessment is out of 100 percentage points.
假设测试或评估满分为100个百分点
Now, how could I go about assigning a grade to the student's score?
那么 我该如何给学生的分数打分呢？
Well in the US, it's very commonly the case
在美国
that if you get between a 90 and 100, that's an A.
如果你得了90到100分 那就是A
And if it's between an 80 and a 89, it's a B. If it's 70 and 79, it's a C,
如果在80到89之间 就是B 如果是70和79 就是C
and so forth, all the way down to F, which should be E,
以此类推 一直到F 应该是E
but we'll see that there's a bit of a jump.
但我们会看到有一点跳跃
So how might I express this?
我该怎么表达呢？
Well, I can use conditionals.
我可以用条件句
And I can ask a few questions and then print out the student's grade
我可以问几个问题然后打印出学生的成绩
accordingly.
相应地
So let me express it like this, if the student's score is
让我这样表达 如果学生的分数是
greater than or equal to 90, and the student's score is
大于或等于90 学生的分数是
less than or equal to 100, so it's in that range, let's go ahead
小于或等于100 所以它在这个范围内 我们继续
and print out that their grade shall be an A. Because they're in the 90s,
并打印出他们的成绩是A因为他们是90年代的
above grades range.
以上等级范围
elif the score is greater than or equal to 80,
如果分数大于或等于80
and the score is less than or equal to, say, 89, but here I have some options.
比方说 分数小于或等于89 但这里我有一些选择
Logically, I can actually express myself in any number of ways.
从逻辑上讲 我实际上可以用许多方式来表达自己
And maybe just to be a little cleaner, I'm
也许只是为了更干净一点 我是
going to say a score is less than 90.
可以说一个分数低于90分
So I'm using less than instead of less than or equal to.
所以我使用小于 而不是小于或等于
So I'm making sure that their boundaries between these grades are correct.
所以我要确保他们在这些年级之间的界限是正确的
Then, I'm going to go ahead and give the student a B if it's in the 80s.
然后 如果是80度 我会给学生打个B
elif score is greater than or equal to 70, and the score is less than 80,
如果ELIF分数大于或等于70 且分数小于80
I'm going to go ahead and give them a C.
我要给他们打个C
elif the score is greater than or equal to 60, and the score is less than 70,
如果得分大于或等于60 且得分小于70
I'm going to go ahead and give him a D. And here's
我要给他打个D 这是
where it's a little anomalous, at least in some schools here, else
这是有点反常的 至少在这里的一些学校 其他
I'm going to go ahead and give them an F. So we're skipping E altogether,
我要继续 给他们F 所以我们完全跳过E
and we're going to give an F, instead, for the grade.
我们要给这个分数打个F
So that's the catch-all.
这就是最重要的问题
And I think, logically, I've gotten this correct,
我认为 从逻辑上讲 我的理解是正确的
at least based on where I went to school growing up,
至少从我在哪里长大的学校来看
such that it's going to give an A, or a B, or a C, or a D,
这样它就会给出A、B、C或D
else it's going to assume that you got an F.
否则 它会假设你得了F
Well, let's try just a few of these here.
好的 让我们在这里只试几个
Let's run Python of grade.py.
让我们运行grade.py的Python
My score is, let's start strong, 100.
我的分数是 让我们开始强势 100分
I got an A. Didn't do as well the next time, maybe it's a 95--
我得了A 下一次没考好 可能是95分--
still an A. Starting to slip further, so I got an 89 the next time.
仍然是A 开始进一步下滑 所以我下一次得了89分
That's now, say, a B. And let's say I really had a bad week,
现在 比方说 A B 假设我这一周真的很糟糕
and it's now a 71.
现在它是71
That's now a C. Or I didn't even submit it at all, that's an F, altogether.
现在是C 或者我根本没有提交 那就是F
So it seems to work.
因此 它似乎奏效了
That's not really an exhaustive test, but at least
这并不是一个真正详尽的测试 但至少
based on some sampling there, my code seems to work as I expect.
根据那里的一些样本 我的代码似乎可以像我预期的那样工作
But let's see if we can't tighten this up.
但让我们看看我们是否能收紧这一点
It's not wrong.
这不是错的
It's correct.
这是正确的
And, indeed, according to my own specifications,
事实上 根据我自己的说明书
I dare say this code is correct.
我敢说这个代码是正确的
But can we tighten it up?
但我们能收紧它吗？
Can we reduce the probability of bugs, now or down the line?
无论是现在还是将来 我们都能降低错误发生的可能性吗？
Can we increase the readability of it?
我们能增加它的可读性吗？
And can we increase the efficiency of it?
我们能提高它的效率吗？
Can we get the computer to have to answer fewer questions
我们能让计算机回答更少的问题吗？
and still get the same result?
还能得到同样的结果吗？
Well, let's see what we might do.
好吧 让我们看看我们能做些什么
Let me just switch things up, if only to demonstrate that we can
让我来改变一下 即使只是为了证明我们可以
use these symbols in different ways.
以不同的方式使用这些符号
I could say, as I've done, if score is greater than or equal to 90.
我可以说 就像我做过的那样 如果分数大于或等于90
But I can actually do this, I can flip it around.
但我实际上可以做到这一点 我可以把它翻过来
Instead of saying greater than or equal to,
不是说大于或等于
let's say 90 is less than or equal to score.
让我们假设90是小于或等于分数
And here, let's say if 80 is less than or equal to score.
在这里 假设80小于或等于分数
And here, 70 is less than or equal to score.
而在这里 70是小于或等于分数
And then, lastly, 60 is less than or equal to score.
最后 60是小于或等于分数
So it's the same thing, logically.
所以从逻辑上讲 这是一回事
I'm just switching things around, just like you could do on paper pencil
我只是在交换东西 就像你在纸铅笔上做的那样
if you really wanted.
如果你真的想的话
But now notice this trick.
但现在请注意这个把戏
And this is not possible, for those of you who have programmed in C, or C++,
这是不可能的 对于那些用C或C++编程的人来说
or Java, or other languages.
或Java或其他语言
Notice what I can do here is actually combine these ranges.
请注意 我在这里可以做的实际上是合并这些范围
Notice that I'm asking two questions, two Boolean expressions.
注意 我在问两个问题 两个布尔表达式
Is 90 less than or equal to score, and is score less than or equal to 100?
90是小于或等于分数 而分数是小于或等于100？
Well, Python allows you to nest these things like this,
嗯 Python允许您像这样嵌套这些东西
and chain them together.
用链子把它们锁在一起
And just like you would on paper pencil in the real world,
就像你在现实世界里用纸笔写的一样
you can encode in Python, do this, which is just a little cleaner.
你可以用Python语言进行编码 这样做会更干净一些
It's tightening up the code a little bit.
它正在收紧代码
It's fewer keystrokes.
击键次数更少
It's faster to type.
打字更快
It's easier to read, moving forward.
向前看 它更容易阅读
So that's arguably better, as well.
因此 这也可以说是更好的
So that's one improvement.
这是一个进步
It's largely aesthetic, in this case.
在这种情况下 它在很大程度上是美学的
It's still asking the same number of questions,
它仍然在问同样数量的问题
but it's doing it a little more succinctly still.
但它更简洁地做到了这一点
Well, what more could I do here next?
那接下来我还能在这里做些什么呢？
Well, you know what?
好吧 你知道吗？
Each time I'm deciding these grades, I don't
每次我决定成绩的时候 我都不会
think I have to ask two questions.
我想我得问两个问题
I don't have to ask, is it greater than 90 and less than 100?
我不需要问 它是大于90 小于100吗？
Is it greater than 80 and less than 90?
是大于80 小于90吗？
If I rethink my logic, I can maybe do this better still.
如果我重新思考我的逻辑 我可能会做得更好
Let me propose that we simplify this further, and just do this.
让我建议我们进一步简化这一点 然后就这样做
If we know that input, for the moment, is going to be within 0 and 100,
如果我们知道 目前的输入值将在0到100之间
we can make some assumptions.
我们可以做一些假设
We could say something like, if the score is greater than or equal to 90,
我们可以这样说 如果分数大于或等于90
well, the student gets an A. elif the score is greater than or equal to 80,
嗯 学生得了A 如果分数大于或等于80
the student gets a B. elif score is greater than or equal to 70,
学生得到B 如果分数大于或等于70
they get a C. elif the score is greater than or equal to 60,
他们得到一个C 如果分数大于或等于60
they get a D, else they get an F. So what have I done here?
他们得了D 否则他们得了F 我都干了些什么？
Well, instead of asking two questions every time,
好吧 与其每次都问两个问题
checking the lower bounds and the upper bound of that range,
检查该范围的下界和上界
I'm being a little more clever here by asking if the score is greater than 90,
我在这里问分数是否大于90是更聪明一点的
well, they've obviously gotten an A or better.
嗯 他们显然得到了A或更好的成绩
If your score is greater than 80, well, you either
如果你的分数大于80 那么 你要么
deserve an A if it's really strong, or a B if it's just above 80.
如果它真的很强劲 就应该得到A 如果它略高于80 就应该得到B
But because of the elif logic, we've already checked
但根据埃利夫的逻辑 我们已经检查过
is the student's score greater than 90?
学生的分数是否大于90分？
And if it's not, then we're asking the question, well, is it greater than 80?
如果不是 那么我们要问的问题是 它是不是大于80？
So you implicitly know it's somewhere in the 80 to 89 range,
所以你隐含地知道它在80到89之间
else you know it's in the 70 to 79 range, else it's in the next range
否则你知道它在70到79的范围内 否则它在下一个范围内
down.
放下
So it's a minor optimization that allows us to ask fewer questions.
所以这是一个很小的优化 允许我们问更少的问题
But again, it's making the code, arguably, a little more readable,
但同样 它使代码更具可读性 可以说
certainly more succinct, an then, hopefully, more maintainable
当然 更简洁 然后 希望 更容易维护
longer term.
从长远来看
Any questions, then, on these types of changes,
那么 关于这些类型的变化 有任何问题吗
and this type of logic with our code?
我们代码中的这种类型的逻辑呢？
SPEAKER 4: What if we don't use elif at all?
演讲者4：如果我们根本不用埃利夫怎么办？
What if we write the code in if?
如果我们把代码写在If里呢？
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, so that's a good question,
大卫·马兰：是的 这是个好问题
because it's actually going to have an unintended effect here.
因为它实际上会在这里产生意想不到的影响
Let me get rid of the F temporarily, and just
让我暂时去掉F 然后
focus on A through D. If we revert to where
把重点放在A到D 如果我们回到哪里
we began today's story, with conditionals, saying if,
我们今天的故事从条件句开始 说如果
if, if, if, now our cleverness here of using broader strokes
如果 现在我们在这里巧妙地使用更宽泛的笔画
and not using an upper and lower bound ranges
并且不使用上限和下限范围
is going to come back to be a downside.
将会带来不利的影响
Let me go ahead and run Python of grade.py.
让我继续运行grade.py的Python
And suppose my score is 95.
假设我的分数是95分
I am so darn excited.
我太激动了
I want my A, but nope.
我想要A 但不是
I just got an A, a B, a C, and a D. So logically, that's broken things.
我只得到了一个A 一个B 一个C和一个D 所以从逻辑上讲 这是坏的东西
Because if you don't make these conditions mutually exclusive,
因为如果你不让这些条件相互排斥
every one of those questions is going to get asked, and therefore answered.
这些问题中的每一个都会被问到 并因此得到回答
And even if your grade is above a 90, it's
即使你的分数在90分以上 它也是
also, logically, above an 80, above a 70, above a 60,
还有 从逻辑上讲 80以上 70以上 60以上
and if I'd kept it in there, I would have failed, as well, with an F.
如果我把它留在那里 我也会以F的成绩不及格
Really good question.
真是个好问题
Other questions here, on this form of logic?
这里还有其他关于这种逻辑形式的问题吗？
SPEAKER 5: Would there be any better way to clean up
演讲者5：还有没有更好的清理方法
even just this simple statement, like we had before,
即使只是这句简单的话 就像我们以前说的那样
the previous one that you had with the elif?
你之前和埃利夫那辆车的那辆？
DAVID MALAN: I like your enthusiasm for simplifying things further.
大卫·马兰：我喜欢你对进一步简化事情的热情
I'm going to go out on a limb here and say this is about as good as it gets,
我要冒险一试 说这已经是最好的了
at least using only conditional statements.
至少只使用条件语句
I can, if my mind wanders, think of a slightly more clever way
如果我走神了 我可以想出一个稍微聪明一点的方法
to do this, maybe with something called a loop,
要做到这一点 也许可以用一种叫做循环的东西
or another programming construct.
或另一个编程构造
We don't have that yet in our vocabulary.
我们的词汇表中还没有这个词
But yes, there's absolutely other ways to do it.
但是的 绝对有其他方法可以做到这一点
But I think not yet if we want to restrict ourselves
但我认为 如果我们想限制自己 还不能
to just words like if, and or, and else, and elif, and and, and the like.
就像If and or Else Elif and and 诸如此类的词
Well, let me propose that we pivot now to use another approach here
好吧 让我建议我们现在开始使用另一种方法
that uses one other symbol that, up until now,
它使用了另一个符号 到目前为止
we've not really had occasion to use.
我们还没有真正有机会使用
Let me propose that we implement a program that we'll call parity.
让我提议我们实施一项我们称之为平价的计划
In mathematics, parity can refer to whether a number is even or odd.
在数学中 奇偶性可以指一个数字是偶数还是奇数
And that's kind of an interesting question.
这是一个很有趣的问题
And it turns out it can be useful in other applications,
事实证明 它在其他应用中也很有用
too, to just ask the question is a given number even or odd,
同样 只要问一个给定的数字是偶数还是奇数
maybe that the user typed in?
也许是用户输入的？
And let me go ahead and write a new program
让我继续写一个新的程序
called parity.py, via code parity.py in my terminal.
在我的终端中 通过代码parity.py称为parity.py
And let me propose that we use this as an opportunity
让我提议我们利用这次机会
to introduce the last of those arithmetic symbols,
为了介绍最后一个算术符号
at least most of which we're familiar with, addition, subtraction,
至少大部分我们熟悉的 加法 减法
multiplication, division.
乘法 除法
But there's been on this list before, this last one here, a percent sign.
但这张名单以前也有过 这是最后一张 百分号
And it doesn't mean percentage in this case,
在这种情况下 这并不意味着百分比
when used as an operator in programming in Python.
在使用Python语言编程时用作运算符
Rather, it represents the so-called modulo operator,
相反 它代表了所谓的模运算符
for modular arithmetic.
用于模算术
Or, at least in our case, we're going to use it to calculate the remainder when
或者 至少在我们的例子中 我们将使用它来计算余数 当
dividing one number by another.
用一个数字除以另一个数字
Well, what do I mean by that?
我这么说是什么意思？
Well, if you take a number like one divided by three,
嗯 如果你取一个1除以3的数字
three does not go into one cleanly.
三不能干净利落地合为一
So you have a remainder of one.
所以你还有剩余的一个
Two divided by three has a remainder of two.
二除以三得余数为二
Three divided by three has a remainder of zero, because it divides cleanly.
三除以三的余数为零 因为它整除
Four divided by three has a remainder of one, because you can divide it in once,
四除以三的余数是一 因为你可以把它除以一
but then that leaves one, so it has a remainder of one.
但这就只剩下一个了 所以它还有一个余数
And then lastly, something like five divided by three
最后 大概是5除以3
has a remainder, of course, of two.
当然 余数是两个
So that's all we mean by remainder, how much is left over
所以这就是我们所说的剩余部分 还有多少剩余
after dividing one number by another.
在用一个数字除以另一个数字之后
Well, if I go back now to my code, and I consider how I might implement
那么 如果我现在回到我的代码 并考虑如何实现
the question is this number even or odd?
问题是这个数字是偶数还是奇数？
Let's consider how we might implement that,
让我们考虑一下如何实现这一点
since it's perhaps not necessarily obvious how we
因为可能不一定很明显我们是如何
can use this additional building block.
可以使用这个额外的构建块
But it turns out it's going to be very useful longer term.
但从长远来看 这将是非常有用的
Well, let's first just get a number from the user in a variable called x.
首先 让我们从用户那里获取一个名为x的变量中的数字
And I'm going to set that equal to the conversion to int
我要将其设置为等于到int的转换
of whatever the user inputs, after asking them what's x, question mark.
无论用户输入什么 在询问他们x是什么之后 用问号
And we've done that before, many times.
我们以前已经做过很多次了
How do I now determine if x is even or odd?
现在如何确定x是偶数还是奇数？
Well, it turns out, if I have access to a programmatic operator that tells me
好吧 结果是 如果我能接触到一个程序化操作员 告诉我
the remainder, I think I can do this.
剩下的 我想我能做到
In fact, let me just ask the group.
事实上 让我问问这群人
And this is just from grade school math, perhaps,
这可能只是小学数学中的一部分
what does it mean for a number to be even, ?
一个数字是偶数意味着什么？
To be clear, a number like 0, 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, 14, 16,
明确地说 像0 2 4 6 8 10 12 14 16
those are all even numbers.
这些都是偶数
But what does that really mean?
但这到底是什么意思呢？
Elena, if I'm saying that right?
埃琳娜 如果我说的对的话？
ELENA: Even numbers that can divide it exactly by two.
埃琳娜：能把它完全除以2的偶数
For example, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 10, and--
例如 2、4、6、8和10 以及--
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
大卫·马兰：太好了
And we could go on all day long, literally,
我们可以一整天 真的
since there's an infinite number of those even numbers.
因为这些偶数是无穷多的
But it's nice that you formulated it in terms of a question
但你用一个问题的形式来表达它很好
that we can ask very clearly.
这一点我们可以问得很清楚
Is this number cleanly divided by two?
这个数字会被2整除吗？
That is, can we divide it by two with no remainder, a remainder of zero?
也就是说 我们能不能把它除以2 没有余数 零的余数？
Well, that's perfect, because if we have this operator, this percent sign, that
这很好 因为如果我们有这个运算符 这个百分号
allows us to answer just that, what is the remainder, we can presumably check
使我们能够回答 剩余的是什么 我们大概可以检查
is the remainder zero, or is it one?
剩下的是零还是一？
Do we have nothing left over, or do we have one left over?
我们是什么都没有剩下 还是我们还有一件？
Well, let's ask that.
好吧 让我们来问问这个问题
If x divided by two has a remainder of zero, as Elena proposes, let's go ahead
如果像埃琳娜建议的那样 x除以2的余数为零 那么让我们继续
and print out something like quote, unquote even.
然后打印出一些类似引用的东西 甚至不引用
And just say as much to the user.
并对用户说出同样多的话
else, I think we can assume that if a number's not even,
另外 我认为我们可以假设 如果一个数字不是偶数
it's going to be odd, if it's, indeed, an integer.
这将是奇数 如果它确实是一个整数的话
So I'm going to go ahead and print out quote, unquote odd instead.
所以我将继续打印引文 不引用奇数
And let's go ahead and now run Python of parity.py in my prompt.
接下来 让我们在我的提示符中运行parity.py的Python
What's x?
X是什么？
Let's start with two.
让我们从两个开始
Two is, in fact, even.
事实上 两个人是偶数
Let's start with four.
让我们从四个开始
Four is, in fact, even.
事实上 四个是偶数
Let's get interesting with three.
让我们来看三个有趣的节目
Three is now odd.
三个现在是奇怪的了
And I think we could do that all day long and hopefully get back, indeed,
我认为我们可以整天这样做 并希望能回来 真的
exactly that answer.
答案就是这样
But what more could we do here?
但我们在这里还能做些什么呢？
How could we improve upon this?
我们如何才能改进这一点呢？
Well, recall that we have the ability to invent our own functions.
好吧 回想一下 我们有能力发明自己的功能
And let me just propose, for the sake of discussion,
为了便于讨论 请允许我提议
that we're going to eventually find that it's
我们最终会发现它是
useful to be able to determine if a number is even or odd.
能够确定一个数字是偶数还是奇数很有用
And so we'd like to have that functionality built-in.
因此 我们希望将该功能内置
And I don't think Python has a function for telling me just that.
我不认为Python有告诉我这一点的功能
But I can invent it using code like just this.
但我可以用这样的代码来发明它
So let me go into my earlier version here.
因此 让我在这里进入我的早期版本
And let me propose that we do this.
让我提议我们这样做
Let me go ahead and write a main function.
让我继续编写一个main函数
I'm going to get back into that habit of defining a main function to represent
我将重新养成定义一个主函数来表示
the main part of my program.
我节目的主要部分
And I'm going to do what I did before.
我要做我以前做过的事
I'm going to get an integer from the user's input,
我将从用户的输入中获取一个整数
asking them what's x, question mark.
问他们什么是x 问号
And then I'm going to ask this question.
然后我要问这个问题
For the moment, I'm going to naively assume
目前 我将天真地假设
that the function already exists, but that's
该函数已经存在 但这是
a useful problem-solving technique.
一个有用的解决问题的技巧
Even if I have no idea yet where I'm going with this,
即使我还不知道我要做什么
how I'm going to invent a function that determines if a number is even,
我将如何发明一个函数来确定一个数字是否为偶数
I'm just going to assume that there's a function called "is even,"
我只是假设有一个函数叫“偶数”
and I'm going to call it, blindly, like this.
我要把它叫做 盲目地 像这样
If is even, passing in x, then go ahead and print quote, unquote even.
如果是偶数 则传入x 然后打印引号 取消引号
So if this magical function called "is even" returns true, as its return value
因此 如果这个名为“is Even”的神奇函数返回TRUE 作为其返回值
I am going to print out that it's even.
我要把它打印出来 它是平的
Else, otherwise, I'm going to assume that it's, of course, odd.
否则 我会认为 当然 这很奇怪
Now the one problem with this program, even if I call main over here,
这个程序的一个问题是 即使我在这里调用Main
is that is even does not exist.
那就是甚至根本不存在
And this program would break if I ran it right now.
如果我现在运行这个程序 它就会崩溃
But that's OK.
但那也没关系
I have the ability, recall, to invent my own function.
回想一下 我有能力发明我自己的功能
So let me define, with def, a function called "is even."
让我用def定义一个名为“is Even”的函数
I want this function to take an argument.
我想让这个函数接受一个参数
And I'm going to call it n, just a number, generically.
我称它为n 一般而言 只是一个数字
I could call it x.
我可以称之为x
But again, I don't want to confuse myself as to which x is which.
但我再说一次 我不想把自己搞糊涂 哪个x是哪个
So I'm going to give it a different name, and that's fine.
所以我会给它一个不同的名字 这很好
I'm just going to call it, more generically, n for number.
我就叫它 更一般地说 n代表数字
And then I'm going to do this.
然后我要做这个
I'm going to say if N % two equals equals zero, just like before, then,
我要说 如果N%2等于0 就像以前一样 那么
and here's the magic, you, the programmer,
这就是魔力 你 程序员
can actually return what are called Boolean values.
实际上可以返回所谓的布尔值
We've seen in Python that Python has stirs or strings, ints or integers,
我们已经在Python中看到 它有搅拌器或字符串、整数或整数
floats or floating point values, all of which
浮点数或浮点值 所有这些
are different types of data in Python.
在Python中是不同类型的数据
Python also has a fourth data type called bool for a Boolean value.
对于布尔值 Python还有第四种数据类型 称为bool
And even though this is just adding to our list, the nice thing about bools
尽管这只是我们清单上的补充 但关于布尔斯的好事情是
is that they can only be true or false.
它们只能是真的或假的
An int can be any number of an infinite possible values.
整型可以是任意数量的无限个可能值
A bool can only be true or false.
布尔值只能为真或假
And it must be capital T and capital F if you're writing itself.
如果你自己写 它必须是大写的T和大写的F
So if I go back now to my code, and I consider
所以如果我现在回到我的代码 我认为
exactly what I want to return here.
这正是我想要在这里归还的
Well, if n % two equals equals zero, that is,
那么 如果n%2等于零 也就是说
if n divided by two has a remainder of zero, well, I think it's even,
如果n除以2的余数为0 那么 我认为它是偶数
to, Elena, your definition.
致埃琳娜你的定义
So let's return true, capital T. else, if it doesn't have a remainder of zero,
所以让我们返回真 大写T 否则 如果它没有零的余数
I'm pretty sure, mathematically, it's got to have a remainder of one.
我非常确定 从数学上讲 它的余数一定是1
But it doesn't matter.
但这无关紧要
I know it's not even, so I'm going to return false.
我知道这不是平均的 所以我将返回FALSE
And we return false, instead capital F. And now that we've defined both main
我们返回FALSE 而不是大写F 现在我们已经定义了两个main
and is even, and I'm calling main at the bottom, I think I've got this right.
而且是平分的 我在底部调用Main 我想我得到了正确的结果
Python of parity.py, Enter.
Parity.py的Python 回车
What's x?
X是什么？
Let's try something simple, like two.
让我们尝试一些简单的东西 比如两个
And it's even.
而且扯平了
Let's do it again.
我们再来一次吧
What's x?
X是什么？
How about four?
四个怎么样？
Even.
不相上下
Once more, what's x?
再问一次 x是什么？
How about three?
三个怎么样？
And it's odd.
这很奇怪
Now, what have I done here?
现在 我在这里做了什么？
I've just made the point that if I want to create my own function called "is
我刚刚指出 如果我想创建我自己的名为“is”的函数
even," that answers this question for me,
甚至 “这为我回答了这个问题
that I can now use, in this program, and heck, maybe future programs
我现在可以在这个程序中使用 也许将来的程序中也可以使用
that I write, I now have a function that no one gave me,
我写的 我现在有了一个没有人给我的功能
I gave myself, that I can use and reuse.
我给了我自己 我可以使用和再利用
And I can even, perhaps, share it with others.
我甚至可以 也许 与其他人分享它
I'm using that function now on line three, just to make a decision.
我现在在第三行使用这个函数 只是为了做个决定
I'm using a conditional up there.
我在上面用的是条件句
And my Boolean expression, something that's true or false,
我的布尔表达式 对或错
is going to be not something explicit, like x less than y,
不会是明确的东西 比如x小于y
or y greater than x, or the like.
或者y大于x 或类似的
It's going to be a function call.
这将是一个函数调用
I'm using a function as my Boolean expression.
我使用一个函数作为我的布尔表达式
But that's OK because I know, because I wrote it,
但没关系 因为我知道 因为这是我写的
that that function "is even" returns true or it returns false.
函数“is Even”返回TRUE或返回FALSE
And that's all I need in a conditional to make a decision
这就是我在有条件的情况下做出决定所需要的
to print even or print odd.
印刷偶数印刷或奇数印刷
So let me pause here to see if there's any questions now on how I've
所以让我在这里暂停一下 看看现在是否有什么问题是关于我是如何
implemented "is even," using this bool.
Implemented“is Even” 使用这个bool
SPEAKER 6: Hello, hi David.
演讲者6：你好 大卫
First of all, thank you for this wonderful class the day
首先 感谢你们今天这堂精彩的课
before yesterday and today, sir.
在昨天和今天之前 先生
I have just one query, based on the background of Java.
我只有一个问题 基于Java的背景
There, when we used to pass the argument,
在那里 当我们用来传递论点的时候
we can also pass the address of the variables.
我们还可以传递变量的地址
So is there any sort of this concept in Python?
那么 在Python中有没有类似的概念呢？
DAVID MALAN: Short answer, no.
大卫·马兰：简单地说 没有
Those who are unfamiliar with Java or other languages, or C, or C++,
那些不熟悉Java或其他语言、C或C++的人
there's generally ways to pass values in different mechanisms that allow you,
通常有几种方法可以通过不同的机制来传递值
or disallow you, to change them.
或不允许您更改它们
In Python, no.
在Python中 答案是否定的
Everything we're going to see is actually, in fact, an object.
事实上 我们将要看到的一切都是一个物体
But more on that down the line.
但更多的是在这条线上
How about time for one more question here on these bools and these
让我们再来问一个关于这些无厘头和这些的问题 怎么样
"is evens."
“是平分 ”
SPEAKER 7: So I actually had a question about defining a function,
演讲者7：我有一个关于定义函数的问题
if that's OK.
如果可以的话
DAVID MALAN: Sure.
大卫·马兰：当然
SPEAKER 7: So if you define one, within your code, like you made it up,
演讲者7：所以如果你在你的代码中定义了一个 就像你编造的那样
are you allowed to use the dot operator like we did name dot strip,
你可以像我们命名点条那样使用点运算符吗
and use it like that?
然后像那样使用它？
DAVID MALAN: Good question.
大卫·马兰：问得好
If you've created your own function, can you
如果你已经创建了你自己的函数 你能
use other functions, like dot strip, or dot title, or dot capitalize,
使用其他函数 如点条、点标题或点大写
that we've seen in the past?
我们过去见过的吗？
You can use those on strings.
你可以把它们用在弦上
Those functions come with strings.
这些函数带有字符串
You can't necessarily use them on your own functions,
你不一定要在你自己的函数中使用它们
unless your function returns a string, for the examples you gave.
除非您的函数为您给出的例子返回一个字符串
I'm returning a bool.
我要退回一笔钱
Bools have no notion of white space to the left or the right.
布尔人对左边或右边没有空白的概念
You can't call strip, you can't call capitalize.
你不能调用条带 你不能调用大写
But if you were writing a different function
但是如果您要编写一个不同的函数
that returns a string, absolutely.
这绝对会返回一个字符串
You could use those functions, as well.
您也可以使用这些函数
Well, let me turn our attention, if I may, back to this example
好吧 如果可以的话 让我把我们的注意力转向这个例子
here, and consider, as we now frequently do,
这里 考虑一下 就像我们现在经常做的那样
can we improve on the design of this code?
我们能改进这段代码的设计吗？
Can I make this particular program better?
我能把这个特别的节目做得更好吗？
And I can.
我也能做到
There's a couple of ways here.
这里有几种方法
And I'll show you something that's now generally known as something Pythonic.
我将向你们展示一些东西 现在通常被称为毕达德式的东西
There's actually this term of art, in the Python world,
在巨蟒的世界里 实际上有一个艺术术语
where something is Pythonic if it's just the way you do things in Python.
如果只是你在Python语言中做事情的方式 那么它就是Python式的
Which is to say, we've seen already there's
也就是说 我们已经看到了
so many different ways to solve certain problems.
有这么多不同的方法来解决某些问题
And in the Python community of programmers,
而在Python程序员社区中
there tend to be some ways that are smiled upon more than others.
有一些方式往往比其他方式更能让人微笑
And they tend to relate to features that maybe only Python has,
它们往往与可能只有巨蟒才有的功能有关
but not other languages.
但不是其他语言
And here's some syntax that you might not have seen in languages like Java,
这里有一些你可能在Java等语言中看不到的语法
or C, or C++ if you've programmed before.
或者C 或者C++ 如果你以前编程过的话
And if you've never programmed before, this too is going to be new.
如果你以前从来没有编程过 这也将是新的
Instead of asking a question like this, if else using four lines, in Python,
不是问这样的问题 如果不是用四行 在Python语言中
you can actually collapse this into just one more elegant line, if you will.
如果你愿意 你实际上可以把它压缩成一条更优雅的线条
Instead of asking if n divided by two has a remainder of zero,
不是询问n除以2是否有零的余数
return true, else return false.
返回True 否则返回False
Let me delete all of that and just say this, return true if n divided by two
让我删除所有这些内容 如果n除以2 则返回TRUE
has a remainder of zero, else return false.
的余数为零 否则返回FALSE
Now those of you who do have prior programming experience
现在 那些有过编程经验的人
might actually think this is kind of cool.
可能真的觉得这很酷
You can condense, from four lines into one line, that very same thought.
你可以将四行浓缩为一行 这是完全相同的想法
And one of the reasons why Python is popular is that it does
而之所以如此受欢迎 其中一个原因就是它确实
tend to read rather like English.
读起来很像英语
It's not quite as user-friendly as most English, or most human languages.
它不像大多数英语或大多数人类语言那样用户友好
But notice, now, the line does rather say what you mean.
但请注意 现在 这句话确实说出了你的意思
Return true if n divided by two has a remainder of zero, else false.
如果n除以2的余数为零 则返回TRUE 否则返回FALSE
That's pretty darn close to something you might say, logically, in English,
从逻辑上讲 这与你可能用英语说的话非常接近
be it about even and odd or really anything else.
无论是关于偶数和奇数 还是其他任何东西
So that program is going to work exactly the same.
因此 该程序将以完全相同的方式工作
Python of parity.py, let me type in two.
Parity.py的Python 让我输入两个
It's still even.
还是扯平了
Let me type in three.
让我输入三个字
It's still odd.
这仍然很奇怪
But I can refine this even further.
但我可以进一步完善这一点
And again, consistent with this idea of not just writing correct code,
再说一次 这与不仅仅是编写正确代码的想法一致
but writing better and better code, but still keeping it readable,
但是编写越来越好的代码 但仍然保持它的可读性
I can do one even better than this.
我可以做得比这更好
Notice this value here is my Boolean expression.
请注意 这里的值是我的布尔表达式
And it is going to evaluate to true or false.
它的计算结果为真或假
Is n divided by two having a remainder of zero or not?
N除以余数为零的2吗？
That is, by definition, a Boolean expression.
也就是说 根据定义 这是一个布尔表达式
It has a yes/no answer, a true/false answer.
它有一个是/否的答案 一个正确/错误的答案
Well, if your Boolean expression itself has a true or false answer,
如果你的布尔表达式本身有一个正确或错误的答案
why are you asking a question in the first place?
你一开始为什么要问这个问题？
Why ask if?
为什么要问如果呢？
Why say else?
为什么要说别的呢？
Just return the value of your own Boolean expression.
只需返回您自己的布尔表达式的值
And perhaps the tightest version, the most succinct, and still readable,
也许是最紧凑、最简洁、最易读的版本
version of this code would be to delete this whole line, Pythonic
这段代码的版本将删除这一整行 Pythonic
though it is, and just return n modulo two equals equals zero.
虽然它是 只要返回n模2等于0
If it helps, let me add parentheses temporarily,
如果有帮助的话 让我暂时加上括号
because what's going to happen in parentheses will happen first.
因为括号中将要发生的事情将首先发生
n divided by two either does or does not have a remainder of zero.
N除以2的余数不是零就是零
If it does, the answer is true.
如果是这样的话 答案是真的
If it doesn't, the answer is false.
如果不是这样 答案就是错误的
So just return the question, if you will.
所以 如果你愿意的话 只要回答这个问题就行了
You don't need to wrap it, explicitly, with an if and an else.
您不需要显式地使用if和Else对其进行包装
And in fact, because of order of operations,
事实上 由于操作的顺序
you don't even need the parentheses.
你甚至不需要括号
So now this is perhaps the most elegant way to implement this same idea.
因此 现在这可能是实现同样想法的最优雅的方式
Now, which is better?
现在 哪个更好？
This is pretty darn good.
这真是太棒了
And it's hard to take fault with this because it's so very succinct.
很难对此负责 因为它非常简洁
But it's perfectly OK, and just as correct,
但这是完全正确的 而且同样正确
to have an if and then an else.
有一个如果 然后是另一个
Even though it might be four total lines, if that helps
即使它可能总共有四行 如果这有帮助的话
you think about your code more clearly, and it helps
您可以更清楚地考虑您的代码 这会有所帮助
other people reason about it, as well.
其他人也会对此进行推理
So it turns out there's another syntax that you
所以事实证明 您可以使用另一种语法
can use to implement the same idea of a conditional,
可以用来实现条件的相同概念
whereby you do something optionally, based on the answer to some Boolean
根据某个布尔值的答案 您可以任选地做一些事情
expression.
表情
And the keyword that you can now use, in recent versions of Python,
在最新版本的Python中 您现在可以使用的关键字是
is called this-- match.
被称为这个--匹配
Match is a mechanism that, if you've programmed before, is similar in spirit
Match是一种机制 如果你以前编程过 它在精神上是相似的
to something called switch in other languages.
在其他语言中称为Switch的东西
For instance, let me go ahead here and close out parity.py And let me go ahead
例如 让我在这里关闭parity.py 然后让我继续
and create a new file called house.py.
并创建一个名为house.py的新文件
And in house.py, I think what we're going
在house.py中 我认为我们要做的是
to do is try to implement a program that prompts the user for their name,
要做的是尝试实现一个提示用户输入他们的名字的程序
and then just outputs what house they're known
然后只输出他们所知道的房子
to be in in the world of Harry Potter.
置身于哈利波特的世界
So for instance, let me go ahead and do this.
举个例子 让我继续这样做
Let me give myself a variable called name, set it equal to the return
让我给自己一个名为name的变量 将其设置为等于返回
value of the input function.
输入函数的值
And I'll say something like, what's your name, question mark.
我会说 你叫什么名字 问号
And then after that, I'm just going to use
然后 在那之后 我会用
a traditional if, elif, else construct to decide what house this person is in.
一个传统的if Elif Else结构 用来决定此人所在的房子
So let me say if name equals equals, say Harry, as in Harry Potter, well,
所以让我说 如果名字等于等于 比如说哈利 就像在哈利波特中一样
let's go ahead and print out Harry's house, which is Gryffindor
让我们继续打印出哈利的房子 也就是格兰芬多
in the world of Harry Potter.
在哈利波特的世界里
elif the name is, instead, Hermione, then
艾莉 如果名字是赫敏 那么
go ahead and print out also quote, unquote Gryffindor,
继续打印 也引用格兰芬多的话
as she's in the same house, too.
因为她也在同一栋房子里
elif name equals equals Ron, let's go ahead
如果名字等于罗恩 我们开始吧
and similarly print out Gryffindor quote, unquote.
同样地 打印出格兰芬多的引语 不引用
And let's make this a little more interesting now.
现在让我们把这个变得更有趣一些
elif name equals quote, unquote how about Draco?
如果名字等于引号 那么德拉科呢？
Draco Malfoy, in the books-- let's go ahead and print out quote,
德拉科·马尔福 在书中--让我们继续打印引文
unquote Slytherin.
引用斯莱特林的话
And just in case someone else's name gets inputted,
以防其他人的名字被输入
for now, let's just suppose that we don't recognize them,
现在 让我们假设我们不认识他们
and say, by default, else print out quote,
然后说 默认情况下 Else打印出引号
unquote who, question mark, just to convey
引述谁 问号 只是为了传达
that we don't actually have a hard-coded response to that particular name.
我们实际上对这个特定的名字没有硬编码的反应
Let me go ahead, now, and run this as Python of house.py, Enter.
现在 让我继续运行它 将其作为house.py的Python运行 输入
And I'll go ahead and type in something like Harry.
然后我会继续输入类似哈里的内容
And voila, we see that Harry is, indeed, in Gryffindor.
瞧 我们看到哈利确实在格兰芬多
Let's run it one more time, Python of house.py.
让我们再运行一次 在house.py中运行一次
Let's type in Draco this time.
这次让我们输入Draco
Slytherin.
斯莱特林
And now, let's type in an unrecognized name.
现在 让我们输入一个无法识别的名字
Let's go ahead and rerun Python of house.py.
让我们继续并重新运行house.py的Python
And let's go ahead and type in Padma, Enter.
让我们继续输入Padma 回车
And who?
那是谁呢？
Because we haven't actually hard-coded with an elif condition in this case,
因为在这种情况下 我们实际上还没有硬编码ELIF条件
what house Padma is meant to be in.
帕德玛应该住在什么房子里
Well, it turns out there's other ways to implement this.
事实证明 还有其他方法可以实现这一点
Indeed, there's some redundancy here, in that
的确 这里有一些冗余 那里有一些冗余
we're checking if Harry, or Hermione, or Ron are all in Gryffindor.
我们正在检查哈利、赫敏或罗恩是否都在格兰芬多
I feel like we can at least tighten this code up a little bit,
我觉得我们至少可以把这段代码收紧一点
using techniques we've seen already.
使用我们已经见过的技术
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续做这件事
Let me go up here and instead do something like this.
让我到这里来 做一些这样的事情
Let's get rid of these two blocks of elifs,
让我们去掉这两块升降器
leaving just Harry's for a moment.
暂时只留下哈里一家
And let's use that "or" keyword again, and say or name
让我们再次使用“or”关键字 然后说或命名
equals equals quote, unquote Hermione, or name equals quote, unquote Ron,
等于引用 不引用赫敏 或名称等于引用 不引用罗恩
thereby consolidating all three cases, if you will, into just one
因此 如果您愿意 将所有三个案例合并为一个案例
if statement.
IF语句
Then we still have a separate elif for Draco because he's not,
我们还有一个单独的埃利夫给德拉科 因为他不是
in fact, in Gryffindor.
事实上 在格兰芬多
And then the final else to catch anyone else.
然后是最后一场要抓住其他人的比赛
Let me go ahead now and run this version of the program, Python of house.py.
现在让我继续运行该程序的这个版本 即house.py的Python
I'll type in Hermione this time.
这次我要输入赫敏的名字
She, too, is still in Gryffindor.
她也仍然住在格兰芬多
Let me try it with Ron.
让我和罗恩试一试
And that, too, still seems to be correct.
而且 这似乎仍然是正确的
Well, it turns out there's another approach altogether that can perhaps
好吧 事实证明还有另一种完全可以
make your code a little less verbose.
让您的代码少一点冗长
You could imagine how complicated this code might
您可以想象这段代码可能有多复杂
get if we had not just Harry, and Hermione, and Ron, but a whole bunch
如果我们不只是哈利、赫敏和罗恩 而是一大群人
of other names as well, for Gryffindor, for Slytherin, and for all
还有其他名字 为了格兰芬多 为了斯莱特林 为了所有人
of the other Hogwarts houses.
霍格沃茨的其他房子
So you could imagine that code just getting pretty unwieldy pretty fast.
所以你可以想象代码变得非常笨拙 很快就会变得非常笨拙
Well, it turns out another technique you can
好吧 事实证明另一种技术你可以
use is, indeed, this keyword called match, which is very similar in spirit,
实际上 使用的是这个在精神上非常相似的关键字Match
but the syntax is different.
但语法是不同的
And it allows you to express the same ideas a little more compactly.
它可以让你更紧凑地表达同样的想法
So let me go back to house.py.
因此 让我回到house.py
And let me propose that I get rid of my current if, elif, else approach,
让我提议我放弃目前的如果 埃利夫 否则的方法
and instead do this.
而是做这件事
Literally use the keyword match, and type the name of the variable,
按字面意思使用关键字Match 然后键入变量的名称
or value, that we want to match on.
或价值 我们想要匹配
And then I'm going to go ahead and include a colon.
然后我将继续 包括一个冒号
And then underneath that, I'm going to include, literally,
然后在下面 我将包括 字面上的
a keyword called case.
一个名为case的关键字
And the first case I want to consider is going to be Harry.
我想要考虑的第一个案例是哈里
And I'm going to put Harry in quotes, because it's a string or a stir.
我要把哈利放在引号里 因为它是一串或一串搅动
And I'm going to have another colon at the end of this line.
我要在这行的末尾再加一个冒号
And indented under that one, I'm going to go ahead and, for now,
在那个下面缩进 我要继续 现在
print out Gryffindor, which, of course, is Harry's house.
打印出格兰芬多 当然 那是哈利的房子
Otherwise, I'm going to have another case for quote, unquote Hermione.
否则 我将有另一个引用的案例 引用赫敏
And similarly, I'm going to have under that indented,
同样地 我将在那个缩进的下面
print quote, unquote Gryffindor, close quote.
打印报价 取消引用格兰芬多 结束引用
Now I'm going to have another case for Ron, also in quotes, with a colon.
现在 我将为Ron提供另一个案例 同样用引号括起来 带有冒号
Now print quote, unquote Gryffindor.
现在打印引用 取消引用格兰芬多的话
And now I'm going to have a other case for, let's say, Draco.
现在 我将有另一个案例 比如说 德拉科
This one gets a little more interesting because Draco, of course,
这一次变得更有趣了 因为德拉科 当然
now is in Slytherin.
现在在斯莱特林
And then I'm going to go ahead and leave it as that for now.
然后 我将继续下去 暂时不谈这件事
So let me go ahead and save this file, and go back down to my terminal window,
因此 让我继续保存此文件 然后返回到我的终端窗口
running Python of house.py, Enter.
运行house.py的Python 输入
And let's go ahead and try Harry.
让我们来试试哈利吧
And he seems still to be in Gryffindor.
他似乎还在格兰芬多
Let's run it again for Hermione, Enter.
让我们为Hermione再运行一次 进入
Gryffindor.
格兰芬多
Let's skip ahead to Draco, and type in Draco's name.
让我们跳到Draco 然后输入Draco的名字
He is, indeed, in Slytherin.
他确实在斯莱特林
Now let's try another name that we haven't handled
现在让我们尝试另一个我们没有处理过的名字
a case for, like Padma again, Enter.
一个案例 就像帕德玛一样 进入
And we're just ignored.
而我们只是被忽视了
There's no output whatsoever because there wasn't a case for Padma.
没有任何产出 因为没有对帕德玛的理由
Now we could, of course, go back in and explicitly add one for Padma.
当然 现在我们可以返回并明确地为Padma添加一个
But what if we, similarly to the else construct,
但是 如果我们 类似于Else结构
just want a catchall that handles anyone whose name is not explicitly specified?
只是想要一个包罗万象的东西来处理任何名字没有明确指定的人？
Well, turns out the syntax for that, using this new match statement,
那么 使用这个新的Match语句 就可以得出这样的语法：
is to still have another case, but then to use
是仍然有另一个案例 但然后使用
this single underscore character, which is used in other contexts in Python.
此单下划线字符 在Python中的其他上下文中使用
But for here, it's meant to say whatever case has not yet been handled,
但在这里 它的意思是说 无论什么案件还没有处理
go ahead and print out, as we did before, for instance,
继续打印出来 就像我们以前做的那样 例如
quote, unquote who, with a question mark at the end.
引用 不引用谁 在末尾加一个问号
Now let's go ahead and rerun this Python of house.py.
现在 让我们继续并重新运行house.py的这条巨蟒
I'll type Padma's name again.
我再打一遍帕德玛的名字
And this time, I think we're at least going
这一次 我想我们至少要
to get an explicit response indicating who,
为了得到明确的回应 表明是谁
whereas previously we did not have the equivalent of that.
而在此之前 我们没有类似的服务
Now, I think we've regressed a little bit.
现在 我认为我们已经倒退了一点
We went from tightening things up by putting Harry, and Hermione,
我们把哈里和赫敏从收紧到收紧
and Ron all on the same line in the same if statement.
和Ron都在同一个IF语句中的同一行
But here, we have now three case statements, again, for all three
但在这里 我们现在有三个案例语句 同样是针对这三个案例
of those.
这些都是
Well, we can tighten this code up, as well.
好吧 我们也可以收紧这段代码
But the syntax is going to be a little bit different.
但语法会有一点不同
I'm going to go ahead and delete these two middle cases for Hermione and Ron.
我将继续删除Hermione和Ron的这两个中间案例
And then up here, next to Harry's name, before the colon,
然后在这里 哈利的名字旁边 冒号之前
I'm going to go ahead and use a single vertical bar, and then
我将继续使用单个竖线 然后
a quote, unquote Hermione.
引用赫敏的原话
Then another single bar and do quote, unquote Ron.
然后再来一节 引用 取消引用罗恩的话
And this is how, using this relatively new match statement,
这就是如何使用这个相对较新的匹配语句
you can say the equivalent of Harry, or Hermione, or Ron,
你可以说相当于哈利、赫敏或罗恩
but more concisely than you could using an if statement
但是比使用if语句更简洁
alone, as we implemented it previously.
单独 就像我们之前实现的那样
So now, one final run of the program with Python of house.py.
现在 使用house.py的Python运行该程序的最后一次运行
Let's make sure that Harry is still in Gryffindor.
让我们确保哈里还在格兰芬多
Let's make sure that Hermione
我们要确保赫敏还在格兰芬多
Let's make sure that Ron is still in Gryffindor.
我们要确保罗恩还在格兰芬多
And indeed, all three of them are.
事实上 这三个人都是
Now, as always with Python and programming more generally,
现在 一如既往地使用Python和更一般的编程
there's going to be different ways you can solve these problems.
你会有不同的方法来解决这些问题
This is just another tool in your toolkit.
这只是您工具箱中的另一个工具
Arguably, it has tightened things up.
可以说 它已经收紧了关系
Arguably, it's perhaps a little more readable
可以说 它可能更具可读性
because there's a little less syntax going on,
因为现在的句法比较少
a little less duplication of equal signs and elif,
少一些等号和埃利夫的重复
and elif, and elif all over the place.
还有埃利夫 到处都是埃利夫
But ultimately, this would be an equally correct approach to that same problem.
但归根结底 这将是解决同样问题的同样正确的方法
But it turns out with a match statement you
但事实证明 使用Match语句可以
can do even more powerful forms of matching, as well.
也可以进行更强大的匹配形式
Here, we've used it simply to implement the same idea as that if, elif,
在这里 我们只是用它来实现相同的想法 如果 埃利夫
else construct.
Else构造
And it's worth noting, if you've programmed in some other language,
值得注意的是 如果你用其他语言编程
the syntax here is, indeed, correct.
这里的语法确实是正确的
You do not need, for instance, a break statement,
例如 您不需要BREAK语句
as has been peppered throughout.
就像从头到尾都在胡椒一样
And you don't need something like default, or something explicit.
而且你不需要像默认这样的东西 或者一些明确的东西
You, indeed, just use this underscore as your catchall at the end of the match.
事实上 你只需在比赛结束时使用这条下划线作为你的总结点
So just by adding in some of these new keywords
因此 只要添加一些新的关键字
here, like if, and elif, and else, we have now the ability
在这里 就像If和Elif 还有其他 我们现在有能力
to ask questions about values.
问一些关于价值观的问题
We have the ability to analyze input from users,
我们有能力分析来自用户的输入
and ultimately make decisions about it.
并最终对此做出决定
And these, then, where our conditionals.
这些 那么 我们的条件句在哪里
Lying ahead is going to be the ability for us to not only use functions,
摆在我们面前的不仅是我们使用功能的能力
and variables, and also these conditionals,
和变量 还有这些条件句
but also, next, loops-- the ability to do something, now, again and again.
接下来 还有循环--现在、一次又一次做某事的能力